Muhammad Ehsaan Khaliq

Lahore, 54590 Punjab, Pakistan +92 334 6846309 Github: meharehsaan LinkedIn: meharehsaan Website: meharehsaan.me Email: ehsmehar@gmail.com

Research Interests

My interests lie in strengthen the digital realm, aiming to contribute to the ongoing enhancement of digital security practices. Research revolves around cybersecurity, particularly in the exploration and exploitation of vulnerabilities embedded within Operating Systems.

Education

Punjab University College of Information Technology

Bachelor of Science - Information Technology

- Expected graduation: July 2024
- GPA: 3.0/4.0

Superior College Burewala

FSC - Pre Engineering

October, 2020 – Present

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

2018 - 2020

Burewala, Punjab, Pakistan

Professional Experience

Teaching Assistant (Operating System)

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

August, 2023 – December, 2023

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

- Designed material and coursework for the newly introduced lab component of the subject
- Designed exam papers for the lab
- Assisted students in the lab + other TA responsibilities

Teaching Assistent (Object Oriented Programming)

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

• Assisted students in the lab + other TA responsibilities

January, 2023 - May, 2023 Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

Skills

Programming Languages: C/C++, Java, Javascript, Python, x86-64 Assembly

Secuirty: Reverse Engineering, Binary Exploitation

Tools: GDB, Ghidra, IDA, Radare Cutter

OS: GNU/Linux, Windows

Research Experience

Linux Kernel Exploitation & Docker Escape (Continue...)

C, Python, x86-64 Assembly

https://github.com/meharehsaan/linux-kernel-exploitation

August, 2023 - Present

• Includes all exploits that I have written during learning binary & kernel exploitation

Term Projects

Socket Programming

Python, Java

https://github.com/meharehsaan/socketprogramming

- In Python sockets File Transfer Protocol FTP, Stop and Wait and Go-back-N protocols are implemented in UDP sockets.
- In java sockets Simple java sockets are implemented using streams in java.

Student Feedback System

Php, Mysql

https://github.com/meharehsaan/feedbacksystem

• Its a secure feedback system for the college faculty. Admin is managing all the things and monitoring the feedbacks. All entites login on the same space.

Extracurriculars & Volunteering

Study Coordinator

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

December, 2023 – Present

Helping Hands - unofficial PUCIT Society

- Faculty Contact: Assist. Prof. Abdul Mateen
- · Organized Study Sessions and webinars
- E.g. Problem Solving and FYP guidence etc

Collaborative Workshop Organizer

PUCIT - University of the Punjab

with Google Developer Student Club

- Organized tech workshops
- E.g. Memory Corruption and Buffer Overflows etc
- https://github.com/meharehsaan/cybersec-workshop